Guide to the 3-D image collection, 1840-2012.
3-D image collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
3-D image collection, 1840-2012.
8080
Speer, Lance
ca. 33 cubic feet.
Photographs, printed materials, toys, cameras, and viewers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection of images and artifacts related to the visual and cultural history of the stereograph and subsequent three-dimensional imaging technologies.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection of images and artifacts related to the visual and cultural history of the stereograph and subsequent three-dimensional imaging technologies covering three eras: the Stereograph Era: 1840-1930; the Bakelite Era: 1930-1960; and the Modern Era: 1960-2012. The collection includes 10,000 photographic stereo views representing a vast array of subjects and geographical locations, 1,200 stereo images in miscellaneous formats, 50 examples of rare stereo formats including daguerreotypes, salt prints, tintypes, ambrotypes, autochromes, kromskop views, tissue views, and glass transparencies, 100 examples of stereo cameras, viewers, and related optical devices, 300 examples of holograms, lenticular images, anaglyphs, films, and 3-D digital images, and 200 magazines, periodicals, catalogs, and books on the history of the three-dimensional image.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Speer, Lance,
Subjects:
Stereoscope -- History.; Photography, Stereoscopic -- History.; Photography, Stereoscopic; Stereoscope
Form and Genre Terms:
History
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
By appointment only.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Stereoview Cards, Photographs, Slides, and Views
Boxes 1-12; 42-48; 57
Flat Cards
Subjects
Geographical Locations
Curved Cards
Subjects
Geographical Locations
War
Lithographic Cards
Oversized
Fine Stereoviews, Kromskop Separations, Daguerreotypes, Glass Stereoviews
Miscellaneous
View-Master Reels
Series II. Stereoscopes and Cameras
Boxes 43-48; 50-59; 63-67
Stereoscopes
Early Stereoscopes
Miscellaneous Stereoscopes
1950s Viewers
Viewers 1950s-2012
Viewer-Master Stereoscopes and Components
Toy Viewers
3-D Glasses
Stereoscopes and View Sets
Boxed Stereoview Card Sets with Viewers
Viewers & View Sets 1950s-2012
View-Master Sets
Cameras
Fine Stereo Cameras
Stereo Cameras and Sets
Stereo Camera Cases and Accessories
Series III. Printed Materials
Boxes 13-15; 18-29; 31-35
Magazines, Booklets, and Comics
Pornography Advertising and Magazines
Catalogs & Booklets
Advertisements and Articles
Science Fiction, Starlog, and Fangoria
Stereo World
Comics
Movie Related
Odds & Ends
Posters
Lobby Cards
Album Covers
Cereal Boxes
Series IV. Lenticular, Holographic, and Anaglyph Processes
Boxes 16-17; 30; 36-41
Lenticular
Postcards
Images & Publications
Holographic
Equipment
Action Figures
Images & Publications
Anaglyph
Images & Publications
Series V. Toys and Novelties
Boxes 58; 60-62
3D Toys and Books
Novelties & Colorforms
Electronic Games
Series VI. Movies and Documentaries
Box 34
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Stereoview Cards, Photographs, Slides, and Views
  - Flat Cards
    - Subjects
      - Advertising (1 card) (Box 1)
      - Animals (14 cards) (Box 1)
      - Blacks (1 card) (Box 1)
      - Boating (7 cards) (Box 1)
      - Bridges (9 cards) (Box 1)
      - Cemeteries (10 cards) (Box 1)
      - Children (25 cards) (Box 1)
      - Children (Hand colored) (12 cards) (Box 1)
      - Disasters & Accidents (6 cards) (Box 1)
      - Erotica (3 cards) (Box 1)
      - Expositions (22 cards) (Box 1)
      - Humor (16 cards) (Box 1)
      - Hunting (3 cards) (Box 1)
      - Interiors (3 cards) (Box 1)
      - Marriage & Courtship (14 cards) (Box 1)
      - Military -- Civil War (6 cards) (Box 1)
      - Military -- Cannon & Guns (2 cards) (Box 1)
      - Painted & Engraved Views (7 cards) (Box 1)
      - Parades & Fairs (2 cards) (Box 1)
      - Photographic (4 cards) (Box 1)
      - Portraiture (7 cards) (Box 1)
      - Portraiture -- Elaborate Studio Settings (6 cards) (Box 1)
      - Portraiture -- House & Yard (9 cards) (Box 1)
      - Portraits -- Business Structures (3 cards) (Box 1)
      - Portraiture -- With Animals (5 cards) (Box 1)
      - Portraiture -- Groups (13 cards) (Box 1)
      - Portraiture -- Famous Personalities (11 cards) (Box 2)
      - Religious (7 cards) (Box 2)
      - Sentimental & Genre (25 cards) (Box 2)
      - Ships (13 cards) (Box 2)
      - Skeleton Leaves (7 cards) (Box 2)
      - Statuary & Sculpture (29 cards) (Box 2)
      - Still Life (10 cards) (Box 2)
      - Theatrical (10 cards) (Box 2)
      - Tissue Views (9 cards) (Box 2)
      - Women (5 cards) (Box 2)
      - Amateur Views (10 cards) (Box 2)
    - Geographical Locations
      - British Isles (30 cards) (Box 2)
      - British Isles (Country & Pastoral)(10 cards) (Box 2)
      - British Isles -- Country -- (G.W. Wilson)(8 cards) (Box 2)
      - British Isles (Ruins)(12 cards) (Box 2)
      - Egypt (5 cards) (Box 2)
      - European Countries (6 cards) (Box 2)
      - France -- Cities & Villas (23 cards) (Box 2)
      - France -- Cities & Villas (15 cards) (Box 3)
      - France -- Country( 3 cards) (Box 3)
      - Germany (11 cards) (Box 3)
      - Greece (4 cards) (Box 3)
      - Holy Land (18 cards) (Box 3)
      - Italy (46 cards) (Box 3)
      - Misc. Countries (10 cards) (Box 3)
      - Switzerland (7 cards) (Box 3)
      - New York -- Rural Scenes (26 cards) (Box 3)
      - New York -- Urban Scenes (4 cards) (Box 3)
      - New York State -- NYC & Vicinity (15 cards) (Box 3)
      - New York State (George Monroe)(6 cards) (Box 3)
      - Niagara Falls -- Falls (11 cards) (Box 3)
      - Niagara Falls -- Bridge (8 cards) (Box 3)
      - Niagara Falls -- Winter (19 cards) (Box 3)
      - Niagara Falls -- Daredevils (2 cards) (Box 3)
      - Niagara Falls -- Niagara River (3 cards) (Box 3)
      - United States -- Washington, DC (3 cards) (Box 3)
      - United States -- Parks (11 cards) (Box 3)
      - United States -- City & Town Scenes (15 cards) (Box 4)
      - United States -- Country & Rural Views (40 cards) (Box 4)
  - Curved Cards
    - Subjects
      - Animals (20 cards) (Box 4)
      - Blacks (4 cards) (Box 4)
      - Boating (2 cards) (Box 4)
      - Bridges (4 cards) (Box 4)
      - Children (44 cards) (Box 4)
      - Disasters (8 cards) (Box 4)
      - Erotica -- Paintings (14 cards) (Box 4)
      - Erotica -- Photographs (14 cards) (Box 4)
      - Erotica -- Showing Some Leg (22 cards) (Box 4)
      - Expositions (16 cards) (Box 5)
      - Genre (9 cards) (Box 5)
      - Humor (23 cards) (Box 5)
      - Ghost Images (8 cards) (Box 5)
      - Hunting (8 cards) (Box 5)
      - Indians (6 cards) (Box 5)
      - Industries (21 cards) (Box 5)
      - Logging (5 cards) (Box 5)
      - Mining (6 cards) (Box 5)
      - Painted & Etched Views (3 cards) (Box 5)
      - Parades (6 cards) (Box 5)
      - Photographic (5 cards) (Box 5)
      - Plants & Flowers (8 cards) (Box 5)
      - Portraiture (14 cards) (Box 5)
      - Presidents (11 cards) (Box 5)
      - Railroads (8 cards) (Box 5)
      - Religion (22 cards) (Box 5)
      - Ships (7 cards) (Box 6)
      - Volcanoes (6 cards) (Box 6)
      - Women (5 cards) (Box 6)
      - Women -- Humor (29 cards) (Box 6)
      - Women -- Marriage & Courtship (18 cards) (Box 6)
      - Women -- Women's Rights (7 cards) (Box 6)
    - Geographical Locations
      - Asia -- Japan (7 cards) (Box 6)
      - Asia -- Philippines (8 cards) (Box 6)
      - Belgium (4 cards) (Box 6)
      - British Isles -- England -- London (8 cards) (Box 6)
      - British Isles -- England -- Rural (4 cards) (Box 6)
      - British Isles -- England -- Cathedrals (4 cards) (Box 6)
      - Great Britain -- Ireland (5 cards) (Box 6)
      - Great Britain -- Scotland & Wales (5 cards) (Box 6)
      - Canada (8 cards) (Box 6)
      - Central & South America -- Mexico (3 cards) (Box 6)
      - Central & South America -- Misc. Countries (14 cards) (Box 6)
      - Egypt -- Pyramids & Sphinx (10 cards) (Box 6)
      - Egypt -- Misc. Locations (13 cards) (Box 6)
      - Europe -- Misc. Countries (3 cards) (Box 6)
      - France (20 cards) (Box 7)
      - Germany (9 cards) (Box 7)
      - Greece (7 cards) (Box 7)
      - Holy Land (21 cards) (Box 7)
      - India (6 cards) (Box 7)
      - Italy (25 cards) (Box 7)
      - Russia (9 cards) (Box 7)
      - Scandinavian Countries (6 cards) (Box 7)
      - Switzerland (12 cards) (Box 7)
      - Misc. Countries (12 cards) (Box 7)
      - United States -- California (4 cards) (Box 7)
      - United States -- National Parks (Grand Canyon) (22 cards) (Box 7)
      - United States -- National Parks (Yellowstone) (13 cards) (Box 7)
      - United States -- National Parks (Yosemite) (10 cards) (Box 7)
      - United States -- National Parks (Yosemite) (26 cards) (Box 8)
      - United States -- New York State (6 cards) (Box 8)
      - United States -- New York City (5 cards) (Box 8)
      - United States -- Niagara Falls (10 cards) (Box 8)
      - United States -- Washington, DC (3 cards) (Box 8)
      - United States -- Misc. States (Eastern States) (16 cards) (Box 8)
      - United States -- Misc. States (Western States) (6 cards) (Box 8)
    - War
      - Boer War (9 cards) (Box 8)
      - Boxer Rebellion (3 cards) (Box 8)
      - Civil War (8 cards) (Box 8)
      - Russo-Japanese War (Japanese Fleet) (1 card) (Box 8)
      - Russo-Japanese War (Artillery & Guns) (2 cards) (Box 8)
      - Russo-Japanese War (Japanese Personalities) (1 card) (Box 8)
      - Russo-Japanese War (Japanese Troops) (7 cards) (Box 8)
      - Russo-Japanese War (Russian Fleet) (4 cards) (Box 8)
      - Spanish-American War (Battleship Maine) (6 cards) (Box 8)
      - Spanish-American War (Civilians) (4 cards) (Box 8)
      - Spanish-American War (Paintings) (4 cards) (Box 8)
      - Spanish-American War (Personalities) (5 cards) (Box 8)
      - Spanish-American War (Points of Interest) (7 cards) (Box 8)
      - Spanish-American War (Wounded & Dead) (6 cards) (Box 8)
      - Spanish-American War (Spanish Troops & Scenes) (2 cards) (Box 8)
      - Spanish-American War (U.S. Troops & Camps -- Cuba) (4 cards) (Box 8)
      - Spanish-American War (U.S. Troops & Camps -- Philippines) (3 cards) (Box 8)
      - Spanish-American War (U.S. Troops & Camps -- U.S.) (19 cards) (Box 8)
      - Spanish-American War (U.S. Camp Block, Peekskill, NY) (10 cards) (Box 9)
      - Spanish-American War (U.S. Naval Ships) (14 cards) (Box 9)
      - Spanish-American War -- Sentimental (2 cards) (Box 9)
      - Turkish-Greek Macedonian War (1 card) (Box 9)
      - World War I -- Misc. (8 cards) (Box 9)
      - World War I -- Regional 300 Card Set Images (49 cards) (Box 9)
  - Lithographic Cards
    - "Around the World" Quaker Oats Series (36 cards) (Box 9)
    - British Isles (10 cards) (Box 9)
    - Central & South America (3 cards) (Box 9)
    - Europe -- Misc. Countries (5 cards) (Box 9)
    - Egypt (14 cards) (Box 9)
    - France (6 cards) (Box 9)
    - Germany (4 cards) (Box 9)
    - Greece (11 cards) (Box 9)
    - Holy Land (5 cards) (Box 9)
    - Italy (14 cards) (Box 9)
    - Japan (7 cards) (Box 9)
    - Kingston Earthquake Series (25 cards) (Box 9)
    - Russia (16 cards) (Box 9)
    - Misc. Countries (25 cards) (Box 9)
    - United States -- California (12 cards) (Box 10)
    - United States -- New York State (2 cards) (Box 10)
    - United States -- New York City (19 cards) (Box 10)
    - United States -- Niagara Falls (11 cards) (Box 10)
    - United States -- Washington, DC (7 cards) (Box 10)
    - United States -- Misc. States (Eastern) (7 cards) (Box 10)
    - United States -- Misc. Western States (29 cards) (Box 10)
    - Advertising Views (2 cards) (Box 10)
    - Animals (6 cards) (Box 10)
    - Animals -- Stockyards (4 cards) (Box 10)
    - Automobiles (1 card) (Box 10)
    - Children (27 cards) (Box 10)
    - Disasters (3 cards) (Box 10)
    - Expositions (8 cards) (Box 10)
    - Flowers & Plants (2 cards) (Box 10)
    - Humor (13 cards) (Box 10)
    - Hunting (7 cards) (Box 10)
    - Marriage (4 cards) (Box 10)
    - Military -- Spanish-American War (6 cards) (Box 10)
    - Military -- Russo-Japanese War (11 cards) (Box 10)
    - Military -- Foreign Views (7 cards) (Box 10)
    - Military -- World War I Series (28 cards) (Box 10)
    - Military -- World War I Views (2 cards) (Box 10)
    - Military -- U.S. Naval Ships Series (14 cards) (Box 10)
    - Military -- U.S. Naval Ships (10 cards) (Box 10)
    - Military -- U.S. Navy -- Shipbown Lithographs (7 cards) (Box 10)
    - Military -- Portraits & Personalities (8 cards) (Box 10)
    - Military -- Misc. Views (15 cards) (Box 10)
    - Oddly Colored Views (16 cards) (Box 10)
    - Painted & Etched Views (3 cards) (Box 10)
    - Photographic (6 cards) (Box 10)
    - Photographically Reproduced Views -- Rare (3 cards) (Box 10)
    - Photo Lithographs (Poor Quality) (5 cards) (Box 10)
    - Portraits (9 cards) (Box 10)
    - Railroads (2 cards) (Box 10)
    - Recreation (5 cards) (Box 10)
    - Religious -- Misc. Views (4 cards) (Box 10)
    - Ships (2 cards) (Box 10)
    - Still Life & Plants (7 cards) (Box 10)
    - Women (29 cards) (Box 10)
    - Women (28 cards) (Box 11)
    - Special Reprints -- Arcade Viewer Images (5 cards) (Box 11)
    - Whiting's Arcade Views (51 cards) (Box 11)
    - Stereo Lithograph Postcards (8 cards) (Box 11)
    - 1/2 Stereo Lithograph Postcards (40 cards) (Box 11)
  - Oversized
    - Expositions -- Centennial Exhibition -- Philadelphia, PA (16 cards) (Box 11)
    - Interiors (3 cards) (Box 11)
    - Portraits -- Groups & Individuals (16 cards) (Box 11)
    - Still Life -- Floral & Funerary Arrangements (7 cards) (Box 11)
    - Misc. Scenes (1 card) (Box 11)
    - Disasters (1 card) (Box 11)
    - U.S. Eastern States -- Cities & Towns (27 cards) (Box 11)
    - U.S. Eastern States -- Country & Rural (13 cards) (Box 11)
    - U.S. Eastern States -- Railroad (5 cards) (Box 11)
    - U.S. Western States (11 cards) (Box 11)
    - Amateur Series -- many 1897 (30 cards) (Box 11)
    - Reprint Cards (4 cards) (Box 11)
  - Reprints
    - Reprints -- Photographic (5 cards) (Box 11)
    - Contemporary Student Views -- 1969 (9 cards) (Box 11)
    - Special Reprints -- Newspaper Content Views (23 cards) (Box 12)
    - Special Reprints -- Photo Effects (7 cards) (Box 12)
    - Special Reprints -- Erotica (22 cards) (Box 12)
    - Special Reprints -- Points of View (12 cards) (Box 12)
    - Special Reprints -- Misc. (53 cards) (Box 12)
    - Erotica -- "Live" Magazine (9 cards), August 1982 (Box 12)
    - Erotica -- "Live" Magazine (12 cards), February 1983 (Box 12)
    - Contemporary Art -- RISD Stereo Art (18 cards) (Box 12)
    - Surface of Mars (12 cards) (Box 12)
    - Deep Space 3-D (4 cards), 1977 (Box 12)
    - Stereoscopics -- Computer 3-D Dimensions (18 cards), 1981 (Box 12)
  - Fine Stereoviews, Kromskop Separations, Daguerreotypes, Glass Stereoviews
    - Eisenhower w/ stereoscope- postcard (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - #2 stereo Kodak- Prospect Park, NY (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Veteran's march stereo views (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Veteran's march stereo negative (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Veteran's march stereo negative (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Still Life stereo negative (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Niagara Falls (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Niagara Falls (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Niagara Falls (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Niagara Falls (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Rural Landscape (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Cut & polished rocks (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Cut & polished rocks (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - View of Town & Lake (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Coastal Scene (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - View of Villa Buildings (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Trees & Valley (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - View Overlooking a Town (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - Stereo Tintgags (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - 1/6 plate Ambrotype - Man-Hidden Stereo (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - 1/6 plate Ambrotype - Man-Hidden Stereo (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - Switzerland Kromscape View (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - Antonine 1914 Antochrome (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - Stained Glass Window Antochrome (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - Parci Antochrome (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - Glass Stereoviews -- two packets (Box 42)
    - Tintype Portraits of 3 people -- paired images (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Views and Slides
    - Box of glass slides (Box 43)
      labelled in French, German, and English
    - Tru-Vue slides (Box 44)
    - Stereo Nudes -- small format (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Misc. Small Stereos (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - EAA Aircraft Stereos (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Misc. Stereo Views/Formats (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Tru-Vue T-16: Roy Rogers in Three-to-One Odds, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Tru-Vue M-1: Robin Hood Fights Little John, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Tru-Vue D-1: Mickey Mouse in "Mickey's Birthday Party", 1953 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Tru-Vue C-4: Children's Fairyland Oakland, California, 1954 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Tru-Vue Around the World Program, England (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Tru-Vue F-1: Cinderella, 1953 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Tru-Vue F-2: Little Red Riding Hood, 1953 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - 3D Stories: Little Red Riding Hood, Captain Radex in Space (Box 45)
    - 3D Stories: Nursery Rhymes, Goldilocks and the Three Bears, The Three Little Pigs (Box 45)
    - 4 boxes stereoscope slides: 2 pinup/pornographic, 1 animals/insects, 1 natural scenery/landscapes (Box 45)
    - Box of stereo protectors and metal plates for slides (Box 46)
    - Charlie's Angels 3D Action Slides (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Charlie's Angels 3D Action Slides (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - View-Master Reels
    - Talking View-Master Reels: Raggedy Ann and Raggedy Andy, 1971 (Box 47)
    - Talking View-Master Reels: The Aristocats, 1970 (Box 47)
    - Talking View-Master Reels: Bambi (Box 47)
    - Talking View-Master Reels: The White House, 1964 (Box 47)
    - Talking View-Master Reels: Star Trek, 1973 (Box 47)
    - Talking View-Master Reels: Mighty Mouse, 1973 (Box 47)
    - Talking View-Master Reels: Disneyland, The Magic Kingdom (Box 47)
    - Talking View-Master Reels: Jungle Book, 1966 (Box 47)
    - View-Master box of 50 packages of reels (21 each), 1957-1980 (Box 48)
    - View-Master box of 50 packages of reels, most with booklets, 1956-1967-1972 (Box 48)
    - View-Master box of 25 packages of reels (21 each), 1958-1980 (Box 48)
    - View-Master box of 99 reels in envelopes (Box 48)
    - View-Master box of 37 packages of reels in envelopes (21 per package), Undated (Box 68)
    - Talking View-Master 3-D Cartridges: The A-Team (3 cartridges), 1983 (Box 48)
    - Talking View-Master 3-D Cartridges: Michael Jackson's Thriller (3 cartridges), 1984 (Box 48)
    - 7 View-Master 7 Reel Packs, 1975, 1978, 1984, undated (Box 48)
    - 3 View-Master 3 Reel Packs (Box 48)
    - 7 Themed View-Master Packs (3 Reels each), 1982-1985, 1995, 2006 (Box 48)
    - George Lewis Collector's Reel (2 reels) (Box 48)
    - View-Master Classic Favorites reels, 2006 (Box 68)
      John Travolta, Kiss and Welcome Back Kotter
- Series II. Stereoscopes and Cameras
  - Stereoscopes
    - Early Stereoscopes
      - 2 large wooden viewers, MU-2737-2738
    - Miscellaneous Stereoscopes
      - Imperial Stereoscope (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - U.S. Army CF-8 Stereoscope (Box 43)
      - Advertising Displays, Inc. Stereoscope (Box 43)
      - Black Stereoscope (Box 43)
      - Unis-France Stereoscope (Box 43)
      - Panorama-Scope (Box 43)
      - Wooden Stereoscope with label: "War Is Declared and the French Go Over the Top to Meet the Enemy: Here they are driving the Germans out of this woods much as we would drive rabbits from a thicket" (Box 43)
      - Superconductivity by Standish D. Lawder: Stereoscope 1-6 (Box 43)
      - Stéréscope Omnium, Brevette S.G.D.G. en France et a l'Etranger (Box 43)
      - Booklet and Viewer: Souvenir of Civic Parade and Installation Ceremonies Honoring the Rt. Rev. Joseph Schrembs, First Bishop of the Diocese of Toledo, Ohio, 1911 (Box 43)
    - 1950s Viewers
      - Radex-Gem Stereo Viewer (Box 44)
      - Modelscope Stereoscope Viewer (Box 44)
      - TDC Stereo Viewer (Box 44)
      - Stereo Realist Handi-Viewer (Box 44)
      - Tru-Vue Three Dimension Film Viewer (Box 44)
      - Tru-Vue 3-Dimension Viewer (Box 44)
      - Realife Stereo Viewer (Box 44)
      - Tru-Vue Stereoscope (Box 44)
      - Delite viewer (Box 44)
      - Craftsmen's 3D viewer (Box 44)
      - Stereoscope Lestrade Simplex viewer (Box 44)
      - 4 Tru-Vue viewers (Box 44)
      - small unlabeled black viewer (Box 44)
    - Viewers 1950s-2012
      - Red Stereoscope (Box 45)
      - Stereopticon 707 (Box 45)
      - Lestrade Simplex (Box 45)
      - The Next Dimension (Box 45)
      - "Mighty Plate" Roof Patch Ad (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Folding Cardboard Viewer (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Stereopticon 707 -- Taylor Merchant (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - Lipton Tea Viewer (Box 45, Folder 16)
      - Stereo Realist scope (Box 53)
    - Viewer-Master Stereoscopes and Components
      - 4 View-Master Stereoscopes, 1978-1990 (Box 46)
        Includes one in the shape of Mickey Mouse and another in the shape of Big Bird
      - 2 lighted View-Master Stereoscopes (Box 46)
      - View-Master box (empty) (Box 46)
      - 3 View-Master Stereoscopes in original boxes, c. 1940s-1950s (Box 47)
      - Early Reel Lists (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Later Reel Lists (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Preview Reels (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - View Master Theater Tour (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - 3 View-Master Stereoscopes in original packaging, 1971-1978 (Box 50)
      - Lighted View-Master Stereoscope in original packaging (Box 50)
      - 15 View-Master Stereoscopes (Box 51)
      - 2 Talking View-Master Stereoscopes (Box 52)
      - View-Master Light Attachment for View-Master Stereoscopes (Box 52)
      - View-Master Stereoscope in original box, c. 1950s-1960s (Box 52)
    - Toy Viewers
      - Big Bird 3D-Camera Viewer (Box 46)
      - Justén Viewer 3D (Box 57)
        blue plastic viewer with story slides
      - Starsky & Hutch 3D Viewer: 24 Scenes, 4 Exciting Shows, 1977 (Box 57)
      - Charlie's Angels 3D Viewer: 24 Scenes, 4 Exciting Shows, 1977 (Box 57)
      - Kingsway 3D Viewer (Box 57)
      - 7 colored plastic viewers (Box 57)
      - The Gooble Gang Giggle Scope (Box 57)
      - Flintstones 3D Viewer, 1977 (Box 57)
      - The Six Million Dollar Man See-A-Show Viewer (Box 57)
      - Scooby-Doo Dyno-Mutt 3-D Viewer, 1977 (Box 57)
      - Animal Crackers 3-D Viewer, 1977 (Box 57)
      - Dragon Master 3-D Viewer (Box 57)
      - Justén Viewer 3D (unpackaged) (Box 57)
      - Spirit: Stallion of the Cimarron Virtual Vision Scopes, 2002 (Box 58)
      - 2 Stereo Viewers (Box 58)
      - Hello Kitty Camera 3-D viewer (Box 68)
    - 3-D Glasses
      - Franchise/Theater Glasses (34 pairs) (Box 59)
      - Polarizing Glasses (10 pairs) (Box 59)
      - Advertising Glasses (32 pairs) (Box 59)
      - Plastic Glasses (8 pairs) (Box 59)
      - Clip-on Glasses (4 pairs) (Box 59)
      - IMAX glasses (Box 68)
        With letter and information text
  - Stereoscopes and View Sets
    - Boxed Stereo Card Sets with Viewers
      - Stereo Book: U.S. Occupied Zone of Germany, c. 1940s (Box 54)
      - The Keystone No. 36 Eye Comfort Stereoscope with the Alpha-Base Out Unit of Slides (Box 54)
      - Holson viewer and slides in faux Ivory box (Box 54)
      - Keystone Home Training Stereoscope with views (Box 54)
      - Keystone View Company: Stereographic Library "Encyclopedia in Picture Form" (Box 55-56)
        7 book shaped boxes includes viewer and 600 views
    - Viewers & View Sets 1950s-2012
      - 3D Photos/Postcards with Stereoscopes (Box 45)
      - 3D Vision: Marsha, Barbi (with red stereoscope) (Box 45)